Matt Rhoades

Wailuku, HI

mtrhoades0727@gmail.com | (919)-906-4188 | linkedin.com/in/matthew-rhoades-6a3b15172/ | github.com/mtrhoades

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

I have been a professional chef for 15 years and am now switching into a career of Software Development. From my previous Chef career I have developed and mastered certain skills such as leadership, organization, and communication from leading teams of cooks and other chefs. I am a recent graduate of UNLV's Software Engineering bootcamp where I learned Full-Stack Software Development. So far I have 1.5 years experience building full stack applications with Javascript as a primary programming language.

EDUCATION

University of Nevada Las Vegas

Full-Stack Software Development Certificate

Coursework: Back-end Development & API's, React & Redux, SQL & Data Modeling,

Programming with Python, Cybersecurity.

Appalachian State University

Business Management

Boone, NC May 2011

Las Vegas, NV

August 2022

SKILLS PROFILE

Certification: Full-Stack Software Development **Programming Languages:** JavaScript, TypeScript

Web Front-end: HTML5, CSS3, React.js, Redux, Bootstrap

Web Back-end: Node.js, Express.js, SQL, MongoDB

Version Control: Git/GitHub, Git Bash

Deployment Tools: Heroku, Netlify, AWS Operating Systems: Linux-Ubuntu, Windows, Mac

Other Skills: REST API's, back-end CRUD routes, Object-Oriented programming,

postgreSQL

PROJECT EXPERIENCE

Cryptocurrency Watch List | UNLV | GitHub Link

May 2022

- Designed and led a team to build a full-stack cryptocurrency watch list
- Utilized React.js, CSS3, and React Bootstrap to build a clean user interface
- Created fully functional back-end CRUD routes and API's using Node.is, Express.is, and SQL

JavaScript Snake Game | UNLV | Deployment Link February 2022

- Designed and built a functional browser-based game
- Utilized HTML5, CSS3, and JavaScript to program a classic snake game based on a UX/UI Rick and Morty theme
- Used CSS grid to create game board, and JavaScript module imports to better organize the code layout

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Kula Lodge & Restaurant, Kula, HI

lune 2022 - Present

Chef

- Led a team of cooks and other Chefs through extensive leadership to conduct a smoothly run operation
- Maintained Inventory and supplies ordering to create a clean organized restaurant environment
- Maintained Employee Hiring and scheduling through transparent communication
- Designed and am currently developing a PERN-stack application for managers and other staff to use through authorization/authentication that will benefit inventory updates, food cost, ordering, employee scheduling, manager logs, and contact information all in one place

320 Main Restaurant, Seal Beach, CA Chef

September 2018 - March 2021

• Led the entire back-of-house operations from dishwasher to line cooks for total kitchen organization

- Created seasonal menu changes to infuse profitably and new customer marketing
- Worked directly with owners to plan certain events and other ways to bring in more income

Bun-Intended Food Truck, Asheville, NC

September 2015 - September 2018

Chef, Co-Owner

- Formed a profitable business serving Southern Thai steam buns and bao
- Managed and planned wedding events, parties, and festivals to sell food at
- Organized business through accounting, employee hiring, inventory maintenance, and social media marketing